export default  [

  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "When was the first version of PowerBI released?",
    "correct_answer": "2013",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "2012",
        "2014",
        "2015"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is Power Pivot?",
    "correct_answer": "It extends the analytical capabilities and services of Microsoft Excel.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It helps to create complex pivot tables",
        "It's the previous name of Power BI",
        "It doesnt exists at all."
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is GetData in Power BI?",
    "correct_answer": "Get Data is a simple icon on Power BI used to import data from the source.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It's a custom function to call an external API",
        "This concept doesnt exists in PowerBI",
        "GetData is a short-cut to combine 2 excels"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Business Analysis, Data Analysis, Data Science",
    "correct_answer": "2013",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Business Analysis, Data Analysis, Application Development",
        "Mobile Applications, Data Analysis, Integration",
        "Data Analytics"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is 'M language'?",
    "correct_answer": "A programming language used in Power Query",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "A language to write machine learning algorithms",
        "M programming language doesnt exists",
        "M language is a dialect used in the middle-east."
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does DAX stand for?",
    "correct_answer": "Data Analysis Expression",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Data Annotation Example",
        "Data And Excel",
        "Data Analysis Experience"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the name of the functionality that allows users to ask natural language questions and get answers in the form of a visual?",
    "correct_answer": "Q&A",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Ask Power BI",
        "Power Answer",
        "Visualize Me"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is NOT the name of a Power BI license?",
    "correct_answer": "Power BI Basic",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Power BI Free",
        "Power BI Pro",
        "Power BI Premium per User"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is NOT a dataset mode in the Power BI Service?",
    "correct_answer": "Real-time",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Import",
        "Composite",
        "DirectQuery"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does 'M' in 'M Language' in Power Query stands for?",
    "correct_answer": "Data Mashup Language",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Data Manipulation Language",
        "Data Minor Language",
        "Mostly used to cleanse data Language"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which one of the following is considered to be an AI visual?",
    "correct_answer": "Key Influencer Visual",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Combo Chart",
        "Azure Map",
        "Deneb"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Whay is a Premium only capability?",
    "correct_answer": "Bring Your Own Key",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "PBI Desktop Incremental Refresh",
        "8 Scheduled refreshes a day",
        "Models lower than 1 GB"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What are the Analytics Runtimes available in Azure Synapse?",
    "correct_answer": "Apache Spark, Data Explorer, SQL",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "SQL, Apache Spark",
        "Apache Spark, Data Explorer",
        "SQL, Data Explorer"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is NOT a type of filter in a Power BI Report?",
    "correct_answer": "App-level Filters",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Page-level Filters",
        "Report-level Filters",
        "Visual-level Filters"
      ]
  },

  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "When was the first version of PowerBI released?",
    "correct_answer": "2013",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "2012",
        "2014",
        "2015"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does .pbit stand for?",
    "correct_answer": "Power BI Template",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Power BI Information Technology",
        "Power BI Technology",
        "Power BI Tool"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What CAN'T you do with Power Query?",
    "correct_answer": "If then else conditions",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Join and append data from multiple data sources",
        "Import Data from wide range of sources",
        "Shape data"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which type of chart should be avoided when communicating data?",
    "correct_answer": "Pie charts",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Bar charts",
        "Line charts",
        "Area charts"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Azure SQL Deployment option(s) belong to the PaaS (Platform-as-a-Service) family?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure SQL Managed Instance + Azure SQL Database",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "SQL Server on Azure VMs + Azure SQL Database",
        "SQL Server on Azure VMs + Azure SQL Managed Instance",
        "All the deployment options"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which technology is often referred to as the power of blockchain with the simplicity of SQL?",
    "correct_answer": "Ledger",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Data Studio",
        "TDE",
        "TLS"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What best describes the Azure Data Explorer service?",
    "correct_answer": "Big data analytics cloud platform optimized for high volume, interactive queries.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Big data storage data optimized for batching non-interactive queries.",
        "Big data solution for data transformations.",
        "Data science platform"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which of the following is an appropriate use case for Azure Data Explorer?",
    "correct_answer": "Log and Text analytics",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "In-memory batching processing of petabytes of information.",
        "Real-time analytics",
        "Deploying machine learning models"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which aspect of an extract, transform, and load (ETL) process makes it unsuitable for Azure Data Explorer.",
    "correct_answer": "High query concurrency.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Long running tasks",
        "Large volumes of data for ingestion.",
        "Microbatching"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What does Microsoft Purview do with the data it discovers from your registered sources?",
    "correct_answer": "It catalogs and classifies the data that is scanned.",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "It moves the data to your Azure subscription, automatically creating the necessary storage accounts.",
        "It performs data transformations to match your on-premises schemas.",
        "It makes your data publicly available"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What aspect of Microsoft Purview is used to configure the data discovery for your data sources?",
    "correct_answer": "Scan rules",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Collections",
        "Classifications",
        "Resource sets"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Data Factory component should you use to represent data that you want to ingest for processing?",
    "correct_answer": "Datasets",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Linked services",
        "Pipelines"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Azure data service would you use to create a graph database?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Cosmos DB",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Blob",
        "Azure Table",
        "Azure Factory"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the range of nodes that a dedicated pool in Synapse have?",
    "correct_answer": "1 to 60",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "1 to 100",
        "1 to 40",
        "1 to 80"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which data redundancy in Azure would you use if you want your data to be repliacated across regions?",
    "correct_answer": "GRS (Geo-redundant)",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "LRS (Locally redundant)",
        "ZRS (Zone redunandant)",
        "CRS (Country redundant)"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which distribution type is recommended when working on a dimension table in a dedicated pool?",
    "correct_answer": "Replicated",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Hash",
        "Robin",
        "Tresor"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which SAP connector in Azure leverages the SAP CDC (Change data capture) capability?",
    "correct_answer": "SAP ODP connector",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "SAP HANA connector",
        "SAP BW connector",
        "SAP BTP connector"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "What is the unique value Prop Microsoft can bring in a SQL migration scenario?",
    "correct_answer": "Leveraging License investments from on-prem into Azure SQL PaaS services",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "License mobility",
        "Free Assessment tooling for Discovery & Planning",
        "Assessment tooling for application profiling"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which feature is not present in Azure Cognitive Services for Language?",
    "correct_answer": "Content Generation",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "(Custom) Named Entity Recognition",
        "(Custom) Text Classification",
        "PII Detection"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which role aside from Insights Reader allows you to view Data Estate Insights when given access on a root level?",
    "correct_answer": "Data Curator",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Data Reader",
        "Data Source Admin",
        "Account Creator"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a type of Integration Runtime in Azure Data Factory?",
    "correct_answer": "Azure-Synapse Integration Runtime",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Integration Runtime",
        "Self-Hosted Integration Runtime",
        "Azure-SSIS Integration Runtime"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which languages are supported in Azure Synapse Analytics Spark Notebooks?",
    "correct_answer": "Python, Scala, SQL, C#",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Python, R, Scala, SQL",
        "Python, R, SQL, C#",
        "Python, R, Scala, C#"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "The Delta Lake framework provides ACID guarantees. What does ACID stand for?",
    "correct_answer": "atomicity, consistency, isolation, and durability",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "atomicity, credibility, isolation, and durability",
        "atomicity, consistency, integration, and durability",
        "atomicity, credibility, integration, and durability"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which data processing technique is optimized to manage large volumes of data?",
    "correct_answer": "Extract, Load, Transform (ELT)",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Extract, Transform, Load (ETL)",
        "Stream processing",
        "ETL & Stream processing"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which one of the following visuals displays major contributors to a selected result or value?",
    "correct_answer": "Key influencers",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Matrix Chart",
        "Column and bar chart",
        "Scatter plot"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which Azure data services support Apache Spark clusters? ",
    "correct_answer": "Azure Databricks",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Azure Cosmos DB",
        "Azure Data Factory",
        "All of them"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "PowerBI",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "question": "Which component of an Azure Data Factory can be triggered to run data ingestion tasks?",
    "correct_answer": "Pipelines",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Datasets",
        "Linked service",
        "None of the above"
      ]
  },




]